# RUKESH BASUKALA

Software Engineer

RukeshB: Github

Rukesh basukala: LinkedIn

Bhaktapur, Nepal : Address

9861550624 : Phone Number

rukeshbasukala@gmail.com: Email

# **SUMMARY**

I am a competent young, energetic, and passionate programmer with more than 1 year of experience in different stacks (i.e java spring boot, Ruby on rails, and angular). recently worked as an Associate Software Engineer at Truemark Private Limited, where I worked on Ruby, Ruby on Rails, and Tailwind CSS. Currently, I am extending my skill set by learning frontend library (i.e React)

# **EDUCATION**

### Khwopa Higher Secondary School

HSEB (2014 - 2016)

### KIST Collage (Purbanchal University)

Bachelor of Information Technology (BIT) ( 2016 – 2021 )

# **SKILLS**

- · Languages and Scripts: Javascript, Ruby
- Framework: Ruby on Rails, Tailwind CSS
- Database: MySQL, PostgreSQL
- VCS: Git.
- Collaboration: JIRA, Trello
- · Designs: Figma

# CERTIFICATIONS

- Java Programming: Solving Problems With Software
- Disaster Management Training
- 1 month of Art and Photography Training
- · Graphic Designing Training

# **HOBBY**

- Watching Movie and Series
- · Drawing And Painting
- · Playing Games
- Coding

# VOLUNTEERING

- Leo Club of Bhaktapur Namaster (1st VP)
- Khwopring Open Rover Ranger Crew (member)
- Subharambha Youth Red Cross Circle ( Board Member )
- Kathmandu Coding Olympics (Volunter)

# **EXPERIENCE**

### **Associate Software Engineer**

#### Truemark Private Limited | May 2022 - May 2023

- interviewed and trained interns under the traineeship program
- Worked as a Full stack developer
- Use Ruby on rails, hotwire, stimulus is, and tailwind css
- Worked on sprint system
- Stack used: Ruby, Javascript, Ruby on Rails, Tailwind CSS, PostgreSQL
- · Documentation and testing: Rspec, swagger

#### **Trainee**

#### F1soft International Pvt. Ltd | Sep 2021 - Mar 2022

- Worked on the Banking system, where my role is to fix the issue I was assigned to and make API documentation and write tests in Backend and fix the issue and integrate API in frontend
- · Worked on the Kanban system
- Stack used: java, spring boot, TypeScript, Angular, MySql
- Documentation and testing: Mokito, Spring REST Docs, swagger

#### Intern

#### Fusemachines Nepal Pvt. Ltd | May 2021 - Aug 2021

- Learn and did tasks of core java, spring boot framework, and MongoDB
- Learn web scraping in Java using jsoup
- Used Mockito to do unit testing and swagger to write API documentation
- Done one final full stack project with different groups of interns ( ui/ux intern, frontend intern, and backend intern ) as a team
- Stack used: java, spring boot, MongoDB
- · Documentation and testing: Mokito and JUnit, swagger

## **PROJECTS**

### **Expenses Tracking System**

### Ruby on Rails(Hotwire), PostgreSQL

It is a personal project, to manage my daily expenses and to learn and become familiar with new technologies in Ruby on Rails, such as Hotwire, stimulus js, and explore other features and tools that I am not familiar with.

### **HRM Clone**

#### Spring boot, MongoDB

HRM is an API created by using spring boot and MongoDB. HRM API is used to track an employee's leave and holiday in an organization and apply for a leave.

#### **Other Project**

- Mero Sahar: Java, Mysql
- Quiz: Laravel, MySql
- LCBN: React
- School Management System: C#, MySql
- Online Book Store: ASP.NET, MsSql
- Online Book Shop: Php, MySql
- Movie Review API: Rails, PostgreSQL
- IP Address Tracker: Angular